Salvatore, Nick, Research files /4249
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Nick Salvatore Research files
1977-1984
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Salvatore, Nick
/4249
35 cubic feet
21 linear ft.
Records (documents).
This collection contains drafts and research materials for the following publications: "Eugene V. Debs: Citizen and Socialist," 1982. Nick Salvatore. "Seventy Years of Life and Labor: An Autobiography," 1984. Samuel Gompers; edited and with an introduction by Nick Salvatore. "We All Got History: The Memory Books of Amos Webber," 1996. Nick Salvatore.
8058611
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 29, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Nick Salvatore is the Maurice and Hinda Neufeld Founders Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations and Professor of American Studies at Cornell University. He did his graduate work at the University of California, Berkeley and came to Cornell in 1981. He is the author of Eugene V. Debs: Citizen and Socialist (1982), which received the Bancroft Prize in History and the John H. Dunning Prize, and We All Got History: The Memory Books of Amos Webber (1996), which received the New England History Association's Outstanding Book Prize. His third biography, Singing in a Strange Land: C. L. Franklin, the Black Church, and the Transformation of America (2005) examines the life of one of the most influential preachers of his generation in the Afro-Baptist tradition. He teaches course in nineteenth- and twentieth century American history.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains drafts and research materials for the following publications:
"Eugene V. Debs: Citizen and Socialist," 1982. Nick Salvatore.
"Seventy Years of Life and Labor: An Autobiography," 1984. Samuel Gompers; edited and with an introduction by Nick Salvatore.
"We All Got History: The Memory Books of Amos Webber," 1996. Nick Salvatore.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4289 P: ILR School Alumni Affairs and Development Photographs /4297: ILR School Biography Files
Salvatore, Nick, 1943-; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8058611
- Debs Research Cards, box 1. (Box 1)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Debs, AFL, Gompers/EVD, Indiana, and DFK (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Terre Haute, Industrial Unionism, IWW, and Trade Unionism (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Leadership (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Negro and Personal (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Political Action, Religion, Social Philosophy (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Other's Response, Women, 1855-74 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: 1875-96, BLF (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: BLF-16, BLF/Federation (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards - C,B,Q Strike (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: ARU (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Socialism 1894-97 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Debs Research Cards, box 2. (Box 2)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Dem. Politics, Populism, and Woodstock (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: 1897-1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Appeal, Class, Cooperation, Decline, Electoral Politics, Ideology (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Land, Membership, Personalities, Political Action (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Populism, Racism, Religion, Southwest SPA v. North (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Unity Conference 1901, West Virginia 1912-13 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: 1865-1900 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Debs Research Cards, box 3; microfilm. (Box 3)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Box 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - EUDEBS Research Cards: Box 4 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Appeal Army from Appeal to Reasons (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets, Labadie Collection (Film reel) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1880 Census Data T.H. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - EUD, Address to Jury 1918 (Film Reel) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - National Convention of the Socialist Party: 1908, 1912 (Film Reel) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Debs penultimate manuscript, 1981; sources. (Box 4)
  - Ded, Contents, Introduction, Title (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Chapter 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chapter 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chapter 3 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 4 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Chapter 5 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Chapter 6 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chapter 7 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chapter 8 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chapter 9 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chapter 10 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Epilogue (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Footnotes 1-5 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Bibliography (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - A (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - B (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - C (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - D (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - DEBs to 1914 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - DEBs to 1926; Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - E to L (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - M to P (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - R (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - S (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - A.M. Simons (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - T (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - U to Z (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Debs sources; thesis, 1997. (Box 5)
  - Thesis Xerox Chapter 6 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - SP/Women (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Labor (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Texas-Oklahoma SPA Locals (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - SPA: Trade Union Leaders (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cost of Living Statistics - Southwest, 1890-1912 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Appeal Army (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Texas SPA - Voting (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Oklahoma SPA - Voting Material (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kansas SPA - Voting Material (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Electoral Politics; Administration; Campaign Platforms (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - ARU (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - WW 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Socialist World (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - SP/Blacks (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Misc. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - EVD - Discussed by Others (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - EVD, 1908 Campaign - ATR; 1909 Speech, FD Warren Case (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings - Mss (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - ISR - Xerox 1912-1914 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - LFM - Women's Xerox Letters (1890) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Clippings: Used Already (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - H.M. Holzman, "The German '48ers" - Wisconsin, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Indiana (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Brotherhood Journals (BLFM, RRTJ, TSJ) (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - SP Electoral Stats: 1900-1924 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Proceedings - BLF (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Strikes in Terre Haute: 188101894 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Census Material: TH 1870-1880, St. Mary's Ohio 1910 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - VL Berger (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - OHO Bransteher (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - George Brewer (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - JRCMS - ISU (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - EVD/TD (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Morris Hillguit (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - SM Jones (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - EV Lux (1910-1913) (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Thomas J. Morgan (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Misc./Ms. Research (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Misc. (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - AM Simons (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - S. Stedman (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Carl D. Thompson (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - W.E. Walling (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - MDC - Jail (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - MDC - Pre-jail, Background (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - MDC - Post-jail (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Misc. also 1945 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - "A Generation in Transition" (1977) by Nicolas Salvatore (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Salvatore cont. (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Misc. (Box 5, Folder 51)
- Gompers sources; research cards; autobiography with foreword by Salvatore, 1984. (Box 6)
  - Gompers Notes (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Gompers - NY Times - 1889-1905 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gompers - NY Times - 1906 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Gompers - NY Times - 1907 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gompers - NY Times - 1908 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Gompers - NY Times - 1909 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Gompers - NY Times - 1910 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Gompers - NY Times - 1911 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Gompers - NY Times - 1912 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Seventy Years of Life and Labor" by Samuel Gompers (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Research Cards (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Amos Webber book; photocopies. (Box 7)
  - "We All Got History" (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - WPC: Women's Club (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - AW Chronicle: Politics, Some Fraternal (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - FDP (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Colonization Meeting (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - AAM (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Chicago (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - FDP (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Banneker Institute: 1850s (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - A/A Baseball Clubs: 1860s (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Photocopies (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Letter Photocopies (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Black and Female Reports (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Treasurer's Report and Notes (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - George H. Ward and Grand Army (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Baptist Church (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Fraternal Order and Vets (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Map of the City of Worchester (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Negros; FL Writers Program (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Notes and Letter Photocopies (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Census and Blacks in Politics (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Oration and Articles: Philadelphia (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Black Reports (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - The Virginia Campaign of John Brown (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Edward Coles Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - A Cycle of Adams Letters (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Court Proceedings (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Negros in the Civil War (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Colored Troops (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - The New York Freeman (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Civil Rights Meetings/National Convention (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Drafts, 1990-1993; Author's notes on Webber Chronicle; Author's critique of 3rd draft, 1993; other critiques of drafts. (Box 8)
  - AW: 1854 v. 118 (I) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - AW: 1855 v. 118 (I) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - AW: 1856 v. 118 (I) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - AW: 1857 v. 118 (I) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - AW: 1858 v. 118 (I) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - AW: 1859 v. 118 (I) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - AW: 1860 v.118 (I) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - AW: 1870-71 v.119 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - AW:1872 v.119 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - AW: 1873 v.119 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - AW:1874 v.119 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - AW:1875 v.120 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - AW:1876 v.120 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - AW:1877 v.120 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Worksheets: Section 1 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Chapter 1: To Random House (10/93) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Chapter 2 (10/93) (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Chapter 3 (10/93) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Chapter 4 (11/93) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Chapter 5 (11/93) (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Chapter 6 (11/93) (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Chapter 7 (11/93) (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Chapter 8 (11/93) (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Chapter 9 (11/93) (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Chapter 10 (11/93) (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Chapter 11 (12/93) (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Chapter 12 (12/93) (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Epilogue (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Abbreviations and Footnotes (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Bibliography (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Chapter 1 Revised (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Chapter 2 Revised (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Chapter 3 Revised (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Chapter 4 Revised (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Chapter 5 Revised (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Chapter 6 Revised (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Chapter 7 Revised (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Chapter 8 Revised (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Chapter 9 (5/93) (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Chapter 10 (6/93) (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Chapter 11 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Chapter 12 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Chapter 1: Draft 1 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Notes for Intro (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Notes for Epilogue (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Rewrite AW: my comments (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - AW: Comments for Rewrite - Spring 1994 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - New York in Progress (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Comments (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Notes on Historians (Box 8, Folder 50)
- Research for and printout of computer analysis of black Worcester in 1880. (Box 9)
  - 104 Family Units (7/15/87): Index Cards (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Black GAR Postco Misc. Index Cards (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Amer. Urban History Syllabus; January 1, 1980 Database Search (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Veterans and Witness List (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Index Card Notes (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - NYC Trip: 1/8-19/89 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - New York Public Library (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - List of Masons (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Washington D.C. Trip (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Tom Wessinger (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Penn Research Trip: 10/88 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Fraternal Lodges: Sheets, Names, Census (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Worcester A/A Church Lists (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - A/A Neighborhood, 2 Ward, Worcester, 1880 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Worcester Demographics, 1880 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - 1880 Federal Census Worcester Blacks (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Webber Research Cards, box 1. (Box 10)
  - Research Cards: Black Community Life, Masons (Black), Masons (White) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Research Cards: Politics, Black Community Life, Amos Webber (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Research Cards: Black Community Life Part 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Research Cards: Black Community Life Part 2 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Research Cards: Fraternal Orders (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Research Cards: Leaders, History (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Research Cards: Politics (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Research Cards: Amos Webber (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Research Cards: Work and Economy (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Research Cards: Virginia 1864-65 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Research Cards: US Army - Texas 1865 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Webber Research Cards, box 2. (Box 11)
  - Research Cards: 5th Mass. Cav. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Research Cards: Black Troops (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Research Cards: Civil War (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Research Cards: Black Community Life Part 1 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Research Cards: Black Community Life Part 2 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Research Cards: Cultural Life (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Research Cards: Demographic Statistics (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Research Cards: Economics (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Research Cards: Fraternal Order Part 1 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Research Cards: Fraternal Orders Part 2 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Webber Research Cards, box 3. (Box 12)
  - Research Cards: G.A.R. Part 1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Research Cards: G.A.R. Part 2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Research Cards: Politics Part 1 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Research Cards: Politics Part 2 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Research Cards: Religion Part 1 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Research Cards: Religion Part 2 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Research Cards: Veterans (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Research Cards: Work (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Research Cards: Boston Advocate, Chronicle, Commentary (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Webber Research Cards, box 4. (Box 13)
  - Research Cards: Continued (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Research Cards: Florida, Memory (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Research Cards: Philosophy (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Research Cards: Personal (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Research Cards: Government Documents (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Research Cards: MSS (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Research Cards: Newspapers, Books and Articles Part 1 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Research Cards: Books and Articles Part 2 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Research Cards: Books and Articles Part 3 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Research Cards: Proceedings, M.A. Thesis, Ph. D. Discussion (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Singing in a Strange Land Research Materials. Box A. (Box 14)
  - Xeroxes: Mississippi (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bolivar County, MS (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Marriage Certificate: CLF/BVS (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - CLF (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Baptist Ministers pre-1900, Bolivar County (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Churches (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - History and Politics (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Xeroxes: Memphis (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Baptist Ministers (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Rev. M.J. Jones (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Rev. Benjamin J. Perkins (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Dr. J.B. Martin (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - NAACP (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Sacred Music (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Social/Cultural Conditions (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Howe Institute (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - A. Philip Randolph (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Social/Political Action (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - A/A Leaders (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - A/A War Finance Committee (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - CLF/New Salem (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Rev. G.A. Long (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Xeroxes: Buffalo (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Black Buffalo (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Demographics: Buffalo (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Race/War/Unions (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - CLF Radio (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Churches/Ministers: General (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - A/A Politics: Buffalo (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Friendship Baptist (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - CLF: Call to Friendship (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - MJJ at Friendship, Buffalo (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - NBC Convention, 1945/CLF Sermon (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Sermons and Preaching (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Xeroxes: Detroit (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Black Churches, Detroit (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Black Churches, Social Action: 1945 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Baptist Ministers, Detroit: 1945 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Revs: Banks; Brado, Jr. & Sr.; Coleman; Hill; Ramsey; McNeil (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Detroit Area Ministerial Groups: 1945 (NBC and others) (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Preaching: Technology, Church as Business (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - RE: Billy Graham (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Church and Ministerial Trouble (all denominations) - Detroit, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Detroiters at NBC (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Church Organizations and Activity (largely Baptist) - 1945 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Radio Minister Survey, Detroit, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Emmett Till Lynching, Detroit Reaction (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - AC Powell/ New Bettel/CLF: 1950s (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - A/A Baptist Women Detroit: 1950 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - CLF: FBI File (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Non-Baptist A/A Ministers, Detroit 1945 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - CLF/NBB: 1945-Oct. 1951 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - CLF/NBB: Oct. 1951-1962 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - CLF/NBB: 1963 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - CLF/NBB: 1970s (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Xerox: Shooting, Trial, Coma 6/79-7/84 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - "Remarks," Rev. Jessie Jackson CLF Service, 8/3/84 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Prophet Jones: At CLF Letter, 6/18/55 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Biographical Portraits: A/A Detroit 1945 (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - A/A Religion: General (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - A/A Religion: General 2 (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - Black Theology Movement (Box 14, Folder 62)
  - Xeroxes: Detroit Demographics 1940 (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - Black Detroit: Urban and Economic (Box 14, Folder 64)
  - Business: 1945-63 (Box 14, Folder 65)
  - Employment: 1945; General (Box 14, Folder 66)
  - Urban Renewal: 1945, General and Housing (Box 14, Folder 67)
  - Neighborhoods/Renewal: Hastings/Twelfth (Box 14, Folder 68)
  - Employment: 1951-55 (Box 14, Folder 69)
  - Employment: 1958-59 Recession (Box 14, Folder 70)
  - Employment: 1961 (Box 14, Folder 71)
  - Employment/NAACP: 1960s (Box 14, Folder 72)
  - Police: 1945 (Box 14, Folder 73)
  - Organizations: Detroit, 1945 (NAACP, CUL, etc.) (Box 14, Folder 74)
  - Race Relations Analysis: 1945 (Box 14, Folder 75)
  - Jesse Jackson/Urban Issues: Late 1960s (Box 14, Folder 76)
  - Blacks and Union Movement (Box 14, Folder 77)
  - 1945-1955: Co AFL/CIO Merger (Box 14, Folder 78)
  - 1955 (Box 14, Folder 79)
  - Black Union Leaders (Alphabetical) (Box 14, Folder 80)
  - Black Political Activity (Box 14, Folder 81)
  - Electoral: 1945-1957 (Box 14, Folder 82)
  - Electoral: 1958-62 (Box 14, Folder 83)
- Singing in a Strange Land Research Materials. Box B. (Box 15)
  - Electoral Politics: 1962 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Electoral Politics: 1963 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Xerox: 1960s, A/A Detroit General (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Cleage, A.B. and Family (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Cleage and Anti-Semitism, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Integration Action: 1945 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Baptist Ministerial Tensions: 1962 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Goal/A.B. Cleage/R&M Henry (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Xerox: 1963 March, Detroit (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Northern CLC, Nov. 1963, CLF/Cleage Split (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Freedom Now Party: 1963 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Now! Magazine 1966 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Malcom X (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - February 1967 Strike (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - 1967 Riot (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Xerox: Post-1967 riot, A/A Detroit (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - CLF/Poor People's Campaign (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Xerox: New Bethel "Incident" 1969 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - National Leaders in Detroit 1945 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Xeroxes: Detroit A/A, 1970s General (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Civil Rights: National (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - M.L. King (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Anti-Vietnam War, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Schools: 1945 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Black Nationalism (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Pre-1960s (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Black Nationalism 1966 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Republic of New Africa: Minutes, Newsletters, Pamphlets (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Robert F. Williams (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Republic of New Africa: MS (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Black Social Life (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Ebony's: Year's Progress (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Sociology of Black Detroit (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Class Issues (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Overviews: Detroit News, 1950 and Detroit Free Press, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Xerox: 1960s A/A Leadership - Detroit (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Youth (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Demimonde and Poor (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Black Cultural Life (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Music: Jazz/Blues/Clubs/"Valley" 1945 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Music: Lyrics and Some Criticism (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Music: Scared 1945 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Aretha, 1958 and Erma, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Popular Culture, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Style (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Literature (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Michigan Chronicle, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Race Consciousness 1945 (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Blacks and Jews (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - National Baptist Convention (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - General (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - NBC Activities: General (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Preachers (National) (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - World Baptist Alliance (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Convention Enrollment (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - Conventions (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - Politics/Civil Rights/Social Issues (NBC) (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - 1953 Election (Box 15, Folder 57)
  - Tenure Issue/1957 Re-Election (Box 15, Folder 58)
  - D.V. Jemison, Presidential Address (Box 15, Folder 59)
  - NBC Split: 1960-61 (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Nannie H. Burroughs (Box 15, Folder 61)
  - NHB: Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - NH Burroughs: Writings/Speeches (Box 15, Folder 63)
  - Annual Reports: Woman's Convention (Box 15, Folder 64)
  - Joseph H. Jackson (Box 15, Folder 65)
  - Civil Rights and Politics: 1963 (Box 15, Folder 66)
  - Presidential Addresses (Box 15, Folder 67)
  - Progressive National Baptist Convention (Box 15, Folder 68)
  - PNBC: Detroit (Box 15, Folder 69)
- Singing in a Strange Land Research Materials. Box C. (Box 16)
  - Gender and Racial Conflict (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - JSTOR: Social Agitation Reports (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Women in Society (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Blacks in Society (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Jazz Development (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "Judaism" Winter 2001 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Black Musical Influences (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Interview with Larry Neal (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Baptist Preachers; Articles (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Negro Journal; J.C. Austin Chronology (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Cooperative Developments in Urban Communities (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Erma Franklin (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Negro/Religious Article Xeroxes (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Community Relations (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Preaching and the Black Middle Class (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Negro Culture and Religion (Box 16, Folder 16)